<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LYNGO</title>
    <description>Lyngo app is the the best way to learn a new language using video content that you already know and love!
</description>
    <link>http://myblog.***.***/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://myblog.***.***/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 14:49:59 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 14:49:59 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accent Reduction: How to Sound Like a Native Speaker</title>
        <description>&lt;h1&gt;Learning a language is exactly like making a cake&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So i’m sure you’ve all heard this one before, right? Okay fine, I made it up but still. Learning a language and making a cake aren’t as different as you might be thinking. Both require fundamental ingredients that compose the whole. Of course to learn a language you’ll need things like grammar, spelling, syntax and vocabulary as opposed to flour, eggs, milk, and sugar. Okay, you get the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, after you mix all of the necessary ingredients and give the cake time to bake (or time to practice - in the case of languages) you will have a fully edible (or speakable) product that is greater than the sum of it’s parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The whole is greater than the sum of its parts.” &lt;strong&gt;-Aristotle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How Important is your accent?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lovely but not completely necessary is the accent. It&amp;#39;s like the frosting on the cake. Oh, frosting. What a marvelous and tasty addition. It just makes the whole recipe a lot sweeter. Literally and figuratively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, you really don’t &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; to have a proper native accent to be able to use a language and be understood. You certainly don’t need a proper accent to read and write in your target language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a lot of ways, having an accent can give you an exotic allure. I wasn’t a believer, myself, but it&amp;#39;s true for me so I can see how when I first started learning French, my American accent was perceived as cute even though to me it sounded horrible. The same thing occured when I listened to my French girlfriend&amp;#39;s accent. I thought it was cute and she hated it. If you&amp;#39;re insecure about your accent, listening to native speaking children can make you feel like a real failure. When you compare your accent to the perfect native accents of children it’s enough to make you want to throw your arms up and quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I an expert on accents? Nope. But I was consistently confused for a native French speaker whilst living in Paris and that’s a pretty exceptional accomplishment considering how judgemental and critical the French can be. It’s not an insult either. How else could they have curated their reputation for refined architecture, cuisine, and style?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to give you some of the tips I used to nail my French accent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;How to improve your accent?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. Spelling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first and most important tip I have for foreign accent reduction is &lt;strong&gt;knowing how the word is spelled&lt;/strong&gt;. Particularly for languages like French, Spanish, and Italian (Romance Languages) the spelling and accents provide a reliable roadmap for pronunciation and once you understand the rules and patterns you can pretty much pronounce any word you can spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could say the same for the English language but unfortunately English spelling can seem entirely random at times. Often the spelling has little to do with the pronunciation. In fact, reading over the words I am writing now, I can imagine alternate pronunciations for many words without valid arguments why words are pronounced one way and not another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word “tomato” actually has &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; accepted pronunciations (the second one is standard in British English but is still frequently used in the United States):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Tomato&amp;quot; version 1
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;audio controls&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/tomato1.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Tomato&amp;quot; version 2
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;audio controls&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/tomato2.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So does the word “the” depending on what follows it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The&amp;quot; version 1
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;audio controls&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/the1.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Context: &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; reason why.&amp;quot;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;audio controls&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/the-reason-why.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The&amp;quot; version 2
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;audio controls&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/the2.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Context: &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; only reason why.&amp;quot;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;audio controls&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/the-only-reason-why.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See what I mean? To be honest English can be a little tricky. I&amp;#39;m not saying this is a characteristic unique to English but since English is my native tongue, it&amp;#39;s easy for me to come up with examples like these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funny/relevant story:&lt;/strong&gt; I was on vacation in Greece with a group of friends. While conversing, one guy, let’s call him Allen, mentions that “strawberries are the epitome of happiness.” Okay, that’s not what he said and I can’t even remember what we were talking about but the important takeaway here is that he pronounced the word “epitome” exactly how it looks on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that’s unclear, have a listen here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incorrect&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;audio controls&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/epitome1.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, the word is pronounced like “epitomie/epitomy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correct&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;audio controls&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;/assets/audio/epitome2.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to be clear: I&amp;#39;m not hating on this guy. It&amp;#39;s just a mistake. This is a native English speaker who has certainly heard the word &amp;quot;epitome&amp;quot; spoken before but could not make the connection between the spoken word and the spelled word. For Allen, these were two different words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moral of the story: English is tricky. Don’t feel bad about your abilities. Every mistake can make you stronger. Don&amp;#39;t stop trying. Frosting is tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. Memorization and Repetition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memorization and repetition of phrases that you hear in movies and television shows. Sure maybe it’s annoying to rewind and play again and again but it certainly does help. Listen carefully and imitate. It’s without a doubt a parrot method and you can do it anytime you’ve got an audio recording handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still not sure if you’re getting it right? Record yourself and listen to yourself. If you can’t hear it coming out of your mouth you can probably hear the mistakes in an audio recording. I know this is hard to do - listening to your own flaws but it’s a sure way to improve. Listen to the original, then you, then the original, then you. Re-record/repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have access to a native speaker, ask them to be extremely picky about your pronunciation and language skills. Promise them that you will not take their criticism personally. Assure them that after mistake number 34 you are not going to start crying, storm out, and end the friendship. When you’ve had enough you can always ask them to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that the most important part of speaking a language is confidence and being understood. Fine-tuning your accent is just icing on the cake you’ve already baked. For some, the joy doesn’t come from the accent at all. Some of us are simply happy to have vocabulary and sentence construction. Others of us become obsessive about speaking like a native (I am guilty of this, myself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things that might make this easier:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tongue and throat control:&lt;/strong&gt; can you roll your &amp;#39;R&amp;#39;s and gargle air with your throat? If you practice these skills in isolation, it will help you master the skills in context.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Musical ability:&lt;/strong&gt; would you say you have a sharp ear for music? When you listen to a song, do you listen to it’s individual parts or do you only hear it as a whole? If you answered yes to bot questions you should have an easier time speaking without an accent. Speaking has a lot to do with listening so a sharp ear for things like music can result in a sharper ear for details in accents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Observe&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here is the story of how I discovered I needed to project my lips in order to speak French with a proper Parisian accent:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am the type of person who enjoys listening to music on public transportation. I learned while living in Paris that I could tell what language people were speaking (English or French) simply by observing the movement of their lips. Speaking French demands a strong projection of the lips to properly pronounce words like “où” or “le.” And it’s not like these two words are rarely used - they most certainly are. And these words are not alone in necessitating a strong lip technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can exaggerate this at first and as you gain confidence you will begin to relax a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/26FPNGFDGShrBFeN2&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;288&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://giphy.com/gifs/love-valentines-day-flirting-26FPNGFDGShrBFeN2&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://myblog.***.***/misc/2016/06/26/accent-reduction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://myblog.***.***/misc/2016/06/26/accent-reduction.html</guid>
        
        <category>regular</category>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learn Two Languages At the Same Time: The Chaining Method</title>
        <description>&lt;h1&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you are moving to a multilingual country, need to pick up a few new languages to communicate with your significant other’s family, or just have a passion for several languages, learning two languages at once does not need to be as daunting as it seems. In this blog I’ll show you a method that will allow you to improve both target languages at the same time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little background on how I developed this method: I started learning French because I lived in Paris for a few months. I intended to perfect my French over the course of two years there. However, circumstances changed and I moved to Berlin just a few months after making real progress in French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously I’d want to learn German while living in Berlin, but I was reluctant to let go of French. I had reached a low B1 [LINK] level in a few months of studying and speaking with random shop owners on the streets of Paris. I could feel that in another few months I’d be fully conversational with a strong but quickly fading American accent. I was already reading newspapers - Proust was in my sights!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put French down for a month while in Berlin. But did I start learning German?- No. My &lt;em&gt;naive&lt;/em&gt; emotion was that picking up German meant leaving French behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day I walked past a Buchhandlung (bookstore in German) and saw a French Introductory textbook. For German people! Et voilà, I had the idea that I could learn German with resources created for native French speakers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Chaining Method&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method is very simple: use material in your L2 to learn your L3. Maybe I lost you already? Let me explain this L thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L1&lt;/strong&gt; = Your native language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L2&lt;/strong&gt; = First language you are learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L3&lt;/strong&gt; = Third Language you are learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, my L1 is English, L2 is French, and L3 is German. We use these abbreviations for convenience, and you’ll see variations of them on a lot of language learning websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important! You need to be at around the B1 level in your L2 to effectively learn your L3. That gets to the crux of why I call this the chaining method: If you are not at B1 level in your L2, then you can start this method with your L1 and L2, then proceed to use L2 to learn L3, and L3 to learn L4, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, if my French was not good enough to read newspapers and have simple conversations, I’d get better at French using resources created for English speakers, and then use French to learn German.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/7uNL0F2Q9uPBu&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/drake-7uNL0F2Q9uPBu&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Got so many chains they call me Chaining Tatum&amp;quot; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://genius.com/Drake-pop-style-lyrics&quot;&gt;Drake - &amp;quot;Pop Style&amp;quot; (2016)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;What You Need&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are tons of articles, books and apps that teach you how to learn a language from scratch. These are the resources I use at the beginning stages of learning a language with the chaining method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.assimil.com/&quot;&gt;Assimil&lt;/a&gt; is the most effective tool I’ve encountered for chaining. I find the progression to be very natural, never feel lost, and learn a lot. Most importantly, I get serious practice in both target languages (more on that later)!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.duolingo.com/&quot;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt; is loved and hated. I love it because it really helps me develop an intuition for a new language. And again, it’s great for chaining. I’m forced to translate between French and German, so my knowledge of both is always being reinforced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ankisrs.net/&quot;&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt; for creating flashcards when you encounter new words in either your L2 or L3. Do not use your L1 for the answer! When I don’t know a word in German, my flashcard has German on the front and French on the back. Same idea but in reverse when I don’t know a word in French.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For learners who complete &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.assimil.com/&quot;&gt;Assimil&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.duolingo.com/&quot;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt;, the next step is to start conversing with native speakers in both languages you are learning. We’ll be writing a lot more on how to find language partners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced:&lt;/strong&gt; films in your L3 with subtitles in your L2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced:&lt;/strong&gt; audiobooks in your L2 with text in your L3. This one is also going to get a dedicated post sometime in the next few weeks. It stems from the L+R method [LINK] that I have been using to take my French from functional to fluent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Daily Routine&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning two languages at the same time sounds like an insurmountable amount of work, but I’ve found it to be quite feasible and fun when using the chaining method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Assimil - the main attraction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assimil is the main driver for my routine in the first ~90 days. Each lesson is meant to be completed in about 30 minutes, but since you aren’t fluent in the L2, I’d estimate it at about 40 minutes (at least for me with French - German). &lt;a href=&quot;http://languagegeek.net/2010/05/12/how-to-use-an-assimil-course/&quot;&gt;Language Geek&lt;/a&gt; has a great post on how to use Assimil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; use Anki to create cards for your L3. It will slow you down to the point of exhaustion because most words will be new to you. And it is contrary to the Assimil method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, do create cards in Anki when you find new words, phrases and grammatical structures in your L2. I am constantly finding things I don’t know in French, even in the introduction of the book. Using Assimil reinforces what I already know in French, forces me to read actively so I can understand explanations about the German language, and exposes me to some new words. It is very effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing I’ve found about using Assimil in French is that I am forced to read actively. How many times have you read a magazine or something on the internet in your L2 only to realize that you haven’t digested any of the unfamiliar content? I’m not a neuroscientist, but I’d imagine that your mind is able to use context to compensate for the things you don’t know. If I am given 400 words of a 450 word article, it is likely that I can guess what it is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, with Assimil I need to truly understand the explanations given on the German language. Reading actively helps me recall new words much more easily when I need them in conversations or messages to friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Duolingo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you’ve completed your lesson of the day in Assimil and need to move on to the things you do in life not related to language learning. As we all do, you find breaks where you can go on facebook, message friends, lurk on reddit, etc. Throw a few lessons of Duolingo in the mix when you can spare some time. Set your L2 as the primary language, and the L3 as the language you want to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m willing to bet &lt;strong&gt;the effectiveness of Duolingo is increased two-fold when using it with your L2 and L3.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Here’s why:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with Assimil, you are forced to read actively. But notching things up another level, you must also &lt;strong&gt;translate actively&lt;/strong&gt;. When I was using Duolingo to learn French I would see the French sentence and mindlessly type out the translation in English. But when I am working between two languages I am not fully comfortable in, I tend to pay very close attention to both languages. I can’t afford to mindlessly type out a sentence in French because there is a high chance it could be wrong. Likewise when translating from French to German - I need to read the French very closely to absorb all of the grammar I am about to ninja translate over to German. You think you really know the subjunctive? Try working between those two languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep going until you finish both Assimil and Duolingo. That will get you to at least B1 in your L3, and it will ensure that you’ve maintained and even improved your L2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, posts on more advanced methods to chain languages will be updated soon. Until then!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://myblog.***.***/misc/2016/06/19/learn-two-languages-same-time-chaining-method.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://myblog.***.***/misc/2016/06/19/learn-two-languages-same-time-chaining-method.html</guid>
        
        <category>regular</category>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Two Secrets That Make Learning A Foreign Language Much Easier</title>
        <description>&lt;h1&gt;I know...&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to stay motivated to learn a language if the learning experience is not both &lt;strong&gt;relevant&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;contextual&lt;/strong&gt;. I learned this from my two and a half attempts at learning &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_language&quot; title=&quot;French Language&quot;&gt;French&lt;/a&gt;. My first experience lacked both &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dictionary.com/browse/context&quot; title=&quot;Context&quot;&gt;context&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dictionary.com/browse/relevance?s=tn&quot; title=&quot;Relevance&quot;&gt;relevance&lt;/a&gt;, the second provided relevance but lacked context, and the final attempt (when I actually did became fluent in French) had both relevance and context. &lt;strong&gt;Let me explain...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Attempt 1: High School&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;No Context, No Relevance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://s1.dmcdn.net/AUtAM/1280x720-cVC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mireille et Marie-Laure from French In Action&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no surprise that my high school language education did not result in bilingualism. I feel like this is probably the case for most high school foreign language students in the United States. To be honest, I don’t even think most teachers expect their students to have a true functioning grasp of the language either (and I was lucky enough to be taught by native French speaker! Imagine the countless students taught by other Americans!). I mean, sure, you might score well on the exams (I certainly didn’t) but it’s unlikely that you have the practical ability to function in that language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking back, learning to speak French in the context of high school could never have worked for me. First of all, I was only speaking French a couple times per week in a classroom where the teacher allowed us to use English as a crutch. Second, and more importantly, I was attempting to learn a foreign language in an environment where that language &lt;em&gt;would not serve me.&lt;/em&gt; When was I going to have the opportunity to truly attempt to express myself or get something done in French while living in the United States? Basically never.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have taken Spanish in high school if it was offered. Instead I was stuck taking French with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_in_Action&quot; title=&quot;French In Action&quot;&gt;Capretz Method&lt;/a&gt;, which I never believed I could truly use, and Latin, which has been “dead” for years. In this way my early language learning attempts were not relevant to me. I am not the kind of person who can just learn something “because.” I need a reason. I need to understand how what I am learning directly applies to something I am interested in. To be honest, even learning Spanish would have been a bit of a stretch because i didn’t have any friends with whom I could speak Spanish so it was another skill that I would be learning “just because.” Don’t get me wrong. I fully advocate for language learning as a way to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/education/2014/sep/04/what-happens-to-the-brain-language-learning&quot; title=&quot;What happens in the brain when you learn a language?&quot;&gt;expand and exercise the mind&lt;/a&gt; but especially when you’re younger, sticking to a language until fluency is pretty rare unless there is a true reason to learn it beyond curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Attempt 2: College&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Relevant But Still No Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://colleges.niche.com/images/standard/47494/?v=a7cc377&quot; alt=&quot;Wesleyan University Campus&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full disclosure:&lt;/strong&gt; learning French in high school wasn’t a total failure. I mean i pretty much failed the class but I managed to retain a few basics, about 70% of a Victor Hugo poem (&lt;a href=&quot;http://poesie.webnet.fr/lesgrandsclassiques/poemes/victor_hugo/demain_des_l_aube.html&quot; title=&quot;Demain Dès L&amp;#39;aube par Victor Hugo&quot;&gt;Demain Dès L’aube&lt;/a&gt; - we had to memorize this for an oral exam), and most importantly I retained the joy I experienced the first time I tried to pronounce French words and the first time I’d heard French being spoken. It is this final reason that motivated me to give French another shot during my final year at university. It also didn’t hurt that I was in the midst an irrational quarter-life crisis which made me decide that I had to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/education/educationopinion/10126883/Why-learn-a-foreign-language-Benefits-of-bilingualism.html&quot; title=&quot;Why learn a foreign language? Benefits of bilingualism&quot;&gt;bilingual&lt;/a&gt; before I was dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Executing the Mission&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first day of class I made it clear to the teacher that I wanted to become conversational by the end of the year, I wanted us to meet for extra time outside of class so that I could speak French more than three times per week and I wanted to move to Paris the following fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;More Relevance: The Opposite Sex&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/9N0XEIDC88ePK&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;327&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://giphy.com/gifs/le-pepe-9N0XEIDC88ePK&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that goal in mind, it was only somewhat difficult to stay motivated learning French while still in the United States. I needed a little bit of extra relevance to stay on track and boy did I find it. That year (like every year at my school) there was a French exchange student. That French exchange student eventually became my girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point French was truly relevant. Not only did I have my mind set on moving to France but having a French girlfriend meant that French could actually serve me in my day-to-day life. Speaking a foreign language in a place where that language is not commonly spoken is like having your own secret code. It’s an amazing feeling. I wanted that with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright enough with the love story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had my relevant reasons to learn French but I was still in need of the context. There’s only so much you can learn in a stateside classroom meeting 40 minutes, 3 times a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Attempt 2.5: Paris&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Relevance and Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/l41lNsmgu4aLV6YBq&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://giphy.com/gifs/paris-france-the-city-of-lights-l41lNsmgu4aLV6YBq&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First of all, how does this &lt;em&gt;very real&lt;/em&gt; attempt warrant only .5?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Because attempt 2.5 is really a continuation of attempt number 2 with a summer in between. When I got to Paris I couldn’t really speak a word of French. Understanding was an entirely different battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevance is huge and context is key.&lt;/strong&gt; Back in high school I never imagined I would have a French girlfriend or live in France so French was just another “thing” and not a tool. Now that I was in France as an au pair and was expected to take care of three unilingual French children, French became a necessity. This was the context that I needed. After a few months and a few meltdowns I had surpassed what I thought was linguistically possible for me and at the 6 month mark I was beginning to feel, dare I say, fluent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Living in Paris satisfied the need both the relevance *and&lt;/em&gt; context.&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning a language broadens the mind and it is easiest when you have a reason. I am not saying you have to move abroad. I was fortunate enough to have had this opportunity but I know it’s not the case for most people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What to do if your next language isn’t spoken around you?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Media&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that learning French in the USA would have been really difficult for me unless I was very interested in watching French series or movies (I wasn’t - I didn’t even know of any good ones). You can expect future articles with foreign language media suggestions (movies, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pocket-lint.com/news/131925-youtube-celebrities-are-a-thing-here-are-the-top-ones-and-tips-on-how-to-be-the-next-pewdiepie&quot; title=&quot;Youtube Celebrities Are A Thing...&quot;&gt;youtube personalities&lt;/a&gt;, and music).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/5ehp67vbvfG00&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/robert-elm-englund-5ehp67vbvfG00&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Movies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t mention this before, but another reason I wanted to learn French was because of a film called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113247/&quot;&gt;La Haine&lt;/a&gt; starring &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001993/?ref_=tt_ov_st_sm&quot; title=&quot;Vincent Cassel&quot;&gt;Vincent Cassel&lt;/a&gt;. I can remember watching this film with my friend Ned and thinking, “damn, these dudes sound cool.” Ned is a friend of mine from high school and at the time we watched this film, he’d recently come back from a 3 month stay on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.de/search?q=french+vineyard&amp;amp;espv=2&amp;amp;biw=1247&amp;amp;bih=1319&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiB7M6Y2anNAhWsAMAKHZR4ACoQ_AUIBigB&quot; title=&quot;Check out these beautiful French vineyards&quot;&gt;French Vineyard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed the subtitles. He didn’t. He kept telling me throughout the film, “dude, if you only spoke French, you’d see how much is lost in these subtitles.” I hated the idea that I was missing the true sentiments expressed on screen. That I was only getting the abridged version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there is a real advantage for anyone wanting to learn english because of the broad reach of american movies/music/cultural artifacts. Most people worldwide are probably already watching an American series with subtitles or dubbed. Let that be your motivation. With subtitles and dubbing, you’re missing out. The true meaning, the way the show was supposed to be consumed, isn’t communicated through subtitles and anyone who knows a second language knows that there are some things that simply cannot be translated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Television Series&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Television series and particularly cartoons intended for children were invaluable to my understanding of French. During my early-stage meltdown in France, I spent entire days looking at a grammar book while watching episodes of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1710308/&quot; title=&quot;Rgular Show&quot;&gt;Regular Show&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1942683/?ref_=nv_sr_1&quot; title=&quot;The Amazing World of Gumball&quot;&gt;The Amazing World of Gumball&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1305826/?ref_=nv_sr_1&quot; title=&quot;Adventure Time&quot;&gt;Adventure Time&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;www.cartoonnetwork.com&quot; title=&quot;Cartoon Network&quot;&gt;Cartoon Network&lt;/a&gt;. Now, all three of these cartoon series are American but they are also popular in France. Normally I can’t stand overdubbing (in the US we are simply unaccustomed to it since pretty much all of our media is created in English) but with cartoons, the mouth movement is much less important. I also make sure to watch &lt;strong&gt;all animated series and movies in French&lt;/strong&gt; if I can find them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Youtube&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Youtube is great. I love watching youtube personalities (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/NormanFaitDesVideos&quot; title=&quot;Norman Fait Des Videos&quot;&gt;Norman Fait Des Vidéos&lt;/a&gt;) in French because I can hear how normal people speak in that country. It’s not &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_persons_fictitious_disclaimer&quot; title=&quot;All Persons Fictitious Disclaimer&quot;&gt;movie-structured language&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not overly dramatic or hard to interpret. It’s raw and it’s real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;iTalki&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends have recommended &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.italki.com/home&quot; title=&quot;iTalki&quot;&gt;iTalki.com&lt;/a&gt; to find tutors. Although that costs money, you can speak with a native for free by organizing language exchanges where you spend some time helping them learn your language, and they in turn help you learn their language. You are in-demand for language exchanges if your native language is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.italki.com/teachers/english/US&quot; title=&quot;Enlgish Speakers on iTalki&quot;&gt;english&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are having trouble finding a community of people who are learning or native in language you are learning, you should consult &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/&quot; title=&quot;Meetup&quot;&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/a&gt;. There is probably already a Meetup for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/find/?allMeetups=false&amp;amp;keywords=language&amp;amp;radius=5&amp;amp;userFreeform=Berlin%2C+Germany&amp;amp;mcName=Berlin%2C+DE&amp;amp;lat=52.516693&amp;amp;lon=13.399994&amp;amp;sort=default&quot; title=&quot;Language Meetups in Berlin&quot;&gt;your target language&lt;/a&gt; but if there isn’t, make one! Be proactive. If you just want to read and write your language you could create a literary Meetup/book club to stay motivated but if you’re like me, the only reason to &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; learn a language is so that you can &lt;strong&gt;speak&lt;/strong&gt;! Meetups are great for that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What does it look like to have context but no relevance?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/EIGCnEVFQUQmY&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/boysnoize-berlin-mayday-EIGCnEVFQUQmY&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks a lot like me living in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berlin&quot; title=&quot;Berlin, Germany&quot;&gt;Berlin&lt;/a&gt; and not speaking more than a handful of German words. Speaking generally, Germans in Berlin (Berliners) consistently speak english fluently. My need for German has been very limited since I arrived here several months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arrival, I was afraid that learning German would mean the death of my French. Untrue. Especially if you use the chaining method [link], and I wasn’t yet sure how I felt about living in Germany so I didn’t really see a need to learn. At the time of this article I have decided that I would like to learn German. Living here, it’s relevance is right around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://myblog.***.***/misc/2016/06/15/two-secrets-that-make-learning-foreign-language-easier.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://myblog.***.***/misc/2016/06/15/two-secrets-that-make-learning-foreign-language-easier.html</guid>
        
        <category>regular</category>
        
        
        <category>misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Can&#39;t Learn A Foreign Language</title>
        <description>&lt;h1&gt;Okay.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the thing. It&amp;#39;s not like it&amp;#39;s crazy difficult or anything. Well it is. But it&amp;#39;s not impossible. The problem is, you&amp;#39;re simply not capable of learning a foreign language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because you just can&amp;#39;t. It&amp;#39;s not a big deal but you just can&amp;#39;t. I don&amp;#39;t even mean to make you feel badly about yourself but learning a new language is unfortunately not for you. Other people can do it. I heard your younger sister is pretty good at it. Oh, and so is that one guy who can&amp;#39;t seem to pronounce your name correctly at the office. Unfortunately, you&amp;#39;re just not. Genetics are a mysterious thing. Give up now and stop wasting your time. The end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just kidding. Of course you can ;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 16:34:25 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://myblog.***.***/language/2016/05/27/why-you-cant-learn-a-foreign-language.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://myblog.***.***/language/2016/05/27/why-you-cant-learn-a-foreign-language.html</guid>
        
        <category>featured</category>
        
        
        <category>language</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
